Bernabe Rodriguez Battenti

Backend Software Developer

■ bernabrb@gmail.com

+542291456155



3+ years of experience in backend development, mostly with Node, NestJS and Kotlin. Relational and non-relational databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DocumentDB, DynamoDB). AWS (lambda, SQS, SNS, S3, DynamoDB, DocumentDB).

English level B2. Italian citizenship and passport.

EXPERIENCE

04/2022 - current Backend Software Developer, Personal Pay - Telecom

Responsible for the development and maintenance of APIs within a microservices architecture using Node.js, NestJS and Kotlin for Telecom's fintech, Personal Pay, a digital wallet with more than 3.5M users.

The services developed by my team include the following functionalities: tax calculations for transactions; accumulation and validation of transactional limits; reporting; QR generation for payments; request, delivery, and activation of physical QRs; management of commission and settlement periods for payments; Checkout API to enable other companies to integrate our payment solution, among others.

04/2021 – 04/2022 Backend Software Developer, *Accenture*

Development and maintenance of IVR (interactive voice response) applications for a bank. Technologies: Convergys InVision Studio (internally manages JavaScript) for the majority of the developments and C# for API consumption.

10/2013 - 01/2022 Independent Business Owner, Argentina Digital Store

Owner of a web-based store specializing in digital products for the gaming industry with over 15,000 successful sales. Responsible for the development and maintenance of the website, social media management, customer service, and inventory & purchasing management.

EDUCATION

2015 – 2020 Bachelor of Business Administration, Univ. Nacional de Mar del Plata

Graduated. Marketing orientation.

2019 – 2020 Associate Degree in Software Development, Universidad CAECE

Partially completed. Progress 40%.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

| 2024 | AWS Certified Cloud Practicioner, Amazon Web Services |
|------|--|
|------|--|

2024 MBA Essentials, The London School of Economics and Political Science

2023 Certificate Program in Applied Data Science, Universidad Austral